[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the record book says you were born in 1900, December 31st.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last day of the year, last day of the month, last day of the century.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here in Portland, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had your parents lived here very long?
[SPEAKER_00]: Pardon?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're all deceased.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know they lived in Portland for a long time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: 37 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, when you were born here, had they been here?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did your dad do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he play ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He worked at a lumber company.
[SPEAKER_00]: Inman Poulson's lumber company.
[SPEAKER_00]: Inman Poulson.
[SPEAKER_00]: In
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they come out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd they come out here for?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, just great wide open spaces, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they can't beat this country as far as I'm concerned.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, that's what a lot of people may like more there.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of people in Chicago like Chicago, New York like New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your dad didn't play any ball, though, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: So where did you develop your skills?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a saddle out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1817, 1818, I pitched semi-probo.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't go to high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to go to work right out of grammar school.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I pitched semi-probo.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was in 1818, right during the war.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was too young to go into service.
[SPEAKER_00]: 17, one more call and I'd have probably gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the First World War.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, in 1920, I used to write, I worked at the paper house there for four years, right on their ball pitcher, and I'd catch two.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway,
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to ride over with my bicycle across the river to Judge McCready, who owned the Portland Baseball Club, to see if I could go to training camp with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd take clippings, you know, from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess he got tired of looking at me.
[SPEAKER_00]: So finally, the day before and after training camp, they called up and decided to go take me to training camp.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1920, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went to Ontario, California.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, oh, I pitched a few ball games down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, some of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there's Colton, and they had some ex-Coast League players.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I pitched for the Dutch on St. Patrick's Day.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Irish was a last year club, and the Dutch was mostly all new.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I pitched for the Dutch, and we beat them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can remember the score, 4 to 3.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I hit a home run myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that decided to keep me a while longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: That old son of mine is my roommate.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I pitched along, and finally we got to the open season at Salt Lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was the manager back then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter McReady.
[SPEAKER_01]: His brother owned it, and he was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: His uncle owned it.
[SPEAKER_01]: His uncle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Opening day in Salt Lake, they had to scrape the snow off the ground, pack it up against the left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Leach's packed house, and Poulsen was pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I put me in the bullpen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hell, I've never been on a ballpark like that in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they cut Poulsen out of their four runs in the first day, and then I go in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They put me in.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I pitched five innings, I didn't get a hit or didn't get a run.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then they decided to keep me a while longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Finally, they sent me up to Vancouver in the WI League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Western International.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I- That'd be a B League, wouldn't it be?
[SPEAKER_00]: Class B or- Class A or B, I don't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, I won 12 and lost 12 up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they recalled me at the end of the year, 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then 1921, I go to training camp and stay with them all year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 13, lost 26, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Detroit bought me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Colette and I.
[SPEAKER_01]: Go ahead.
[SPEAKER_01]: Detroit bought you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who scouted you for Detroit?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember anybody in particular?
[SPEAKER_00]: Her, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Betty Her.
[SPEAKER_00]: Way back.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was quite a ways back.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was 1922 when I went up.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did they pay for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: $40,000, eight ball players.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eight ball players?
[SPEAKER_00]: And $40,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Collette and I were the two of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Herman Collette?
[SPEAKER_00]: Herman Collette.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Herman, in 1922, he had a good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he won 19.
[SPEAKER_01]: With Detroit?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won seven and three.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got my wrist broke right in the spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I wound up one seven How'd you break your wrist that hit a pitch ball a pitch ball, yeah Pitching against some club down in Barnstorming up through what I was cold.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went back like that I Come back to 23, how'd you like Ty Cobb to play for?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I've played a lot better
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a fighting manager, I'll tell you what I mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd cut his own mother to get in base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Personally, you can't take it away from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: But other than that, well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't really managerial caliber, though, do you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he's too good a player to be a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, but he's a little truer than that, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he give you any?
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, I was with him for 22, 1922, 23, 24.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then in 25, in the spring of the year 25, I was pitching in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a big lead going in the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bibb Falk hit a line drive.
[SPEAKER_00]: It hit me right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fractured eight bones.
[SPEAKER_01]: On your left cheek.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball rolled over to the first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Blue, Blue picked the ball up and knocked me down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bibb Falk hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a line drive.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a flash.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought I had it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, my.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fred Haney was on third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come over.
[SPEAKER_00]: Passer was catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come over and got a hold of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Blood was just pouring out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got me down to Mercy Hospital there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to get in there and push the bones out.
[SPEAKER_00]: They thought they'd have to wire them, but they didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because all I could eat was soup.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see how we're sounding.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, at 25, after that happened, I thought I was through, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long in the hospital?
[SPEAKER_00]: 11 days.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you unconscious?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: No?
[SPEAKER_00]: Something.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was in the hospital, and Judge Landis, he come up to see me, and a couple of the umpires, the cop never came up.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to leave right away to go east.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had a flash in Detroit that when I got hit, you know, Heidi Manoush was out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He told my wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so she came right down.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as quick as she'd get there, Judge Landis told him and said, give her anything she wants.
[SPEAKER_00]: So anyway, I went out to start farming out to Vernon.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they traded me for Jackie Warner.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went and went to Detroit, and then I went out right to Vernon.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch for Vernon that year, then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got recovered, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's at 25.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the fall of the year, I think I had a pretty good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: After I come back, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you gun shy at all about pitching outside?
[SPEAKER_00]: It all healed up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did it bother you, though, to be here?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, and then in the fall of 25, Cardinals drafted me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Barrett.
[SPEAKER_00]: You probably know Charlie Barrett.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a scout.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then I went to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the best ball I ever pitched in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: It hit me there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because it gave you a good break?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Vernon and then I went to the Cardinals with the four World Series pennants.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had some good years there.
[SPEAKER_01]: 26 and 27, you didn't fight and pitch much, would you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you on the roster, though?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: 27, they farmed me out to Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't they pitch you much?
[SPEAKER_01]: They have a pretty good staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had a good staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: They thought I was like a 26.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hallahan and I, both of us, we'd never get much pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had Alexander.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Grover Alexander.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jess Haynes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jess Haynes, Bill Sherdell, and Cliff Graham.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wow.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they had a good staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a pretty good staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they had a good staff.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you at the World Series?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you still on the roster during the 26th World Series?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: But they sent me home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, you didn't stay on.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sent me home.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when O'Farrell hit a line drive, hit me right on the cockeyed hand, broke my hand here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Roger Horsley said, if you can't do anything more the rest of the year, you might as well go home.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this in batting practice?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll guarantee you, if we win the pennant or anything, if Buddy gets you, get to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: We did.
[SPEAKER_00]: We won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, I got radios.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got the World Series checked.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was 1926.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of your injuries have been hit by batted balls, haven't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Twice in the hand and the face?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I got hit in the shins.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, in 27 I had a good year at Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched a no-hit game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I beat Buffalo 2-0.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I had this and that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty good ball propel up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you win, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: How many did you win, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: 15, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: 15, a low-hit game, and then I joined them in the last of 1927.
[SPEAKER_00]: Come back, and I just fished a little bit every season.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then, 28, I fished quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of relief work.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd start, and I went 28 a couple times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Relieved Alexander once, and went on for 20.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, since the Pettiton in Boston,
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we went down to New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we came home in 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went to Pettit again in 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went to Pettit in 1931.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then in 1931, I traded to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: O'Farrell and I went over to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a trade, and they sent the car to Little Shumrick.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Clanhands, Heinrich Schubel.
[SPEAKER_00]: I traded for Johnny Moore and I had some of the best years of the old Phillies.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about those good years with St. Louis, though, and the Gas House Gang.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come just about when I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had Pepper Martin and Frankie Frisch.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had some pretty wild ones there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was quite a ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Dizzy, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came up late in 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't eligible for the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then after that, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch in any of those series of 30 and 31?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started the third one, I think it was, got beat three to nothing against Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: A tough team, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they were a pretty club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had Grove and Earnshaw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jimmy Fox, and Cochran.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you got a pitch to Simmons, and Fox, and Cochran.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have a break in that lineup, do you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not much.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Fox had a home runoff.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was going right over the roof of that Shy Park.
[SPEAKER_00]: But a lot of people don't know it, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in, what year was I, 28?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, 32?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it 32 when we were playing Boston at Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, that's Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last year, he played ball with Boston, the Braves.
[SPEAKER_01]: That'd be 35, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it 35?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm getting all balled up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he played his last year of the Yankees at 34.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to think.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was my last year with the?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 35, I guess it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: But my last year was 1940 up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was the last one to ever pitch to him, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I struck out the last time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I struck out the last two times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last time, well, if he comes by and pitches, I said, if I can't hit those kind of kids, I'm gone flying.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I threw my high fast ball, you know, and he never hit a home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: The only major league player who never hit a home run is Baker Pohl.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's just a fan box.
[SPEAKER_00]: The left field, the right field, they had that big, looked like a three-stop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, ten.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you could see tents all around it where Chuck Cline and those left-hand hitters used to... Yeah, how do you pitch in a place like that where you have a...
[SPEAKER_00]: Throw your best pitch and back up to third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about the best thing I can say.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to keep it to those left-hand hitters really away from it, you know?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, you pitch away and groove that pitch over to the inside and let them pull.
[SPEAKER_01]: Groove?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's hit a couple of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's still up in orbit, you know, flying around up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's got to be hard on the pitcher, though, to know that that field is so close out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess you just have to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had pretty good luck with Dave.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd pitch him inside.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to pitch him outside.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a little dangerous.
[SPEAKER_01]: Schumrich was saying he played Philadelphia there and hit a right-hand hitter, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was able to put him
[SPEAKER_01]: Against that wall pretty well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't that far that the right-hand hitters couldn't hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, right-hand hitters couldn't hit them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Against their west, they'd hit a lot up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: West and down Hurston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, a lot of those fellas didn't learn to hit that outside pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they tried to pitch inside to them, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the low-ball pitchers, you know, second-ball pitchers, they had a lot better luck, because they hit the ball on the ground.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was higher.
[SPEAKER_00]: part of a high fastball pitcher that hit fly balls.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this has almost all the relief work I did, which was an awful lot of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd go in with men on bases that pitched my strength, high fastballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's logical for a curveball hitting the ground or a sinker to make them hit the ball on the ground.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was throwing my best pitches, and they had to hit in.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was it.
[SPEAKER_00]: My fastball used to raise.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd hit under it.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you came up first back with the Tigers, did anybody give you any help in your pitching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you at least have to pick it up on your own?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mostly, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, we'd have meetings and all this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the pitchers for Detroit then?
[SPEAKER_00]: George Dowse, Howard Empey.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they give you any help or tips?
[SPEAKER_00]: Red Oldham.
[SPEAKER_00]: And her and Paulette, of course, we were buddies.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Burt Cole.
[SPEAKER_01]: And King Cole.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Burt Cole, and George Dallas, Dutch Leonard, and Howard Empty, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: I understood the group.
[SPEAKER_00]: And our outfielder was Beach, Cobb, and Heilman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou Blue was on first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cutshaw was on second.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rick Me on short.
[SPEAKER_00]: McManus?
[SPEAKER_00]: Jones on third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Passer, Mannion, and Widow were our catchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can remember that club pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Marty McManus come up, or Moriarty?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they were the Browns.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moriarty came over later, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Catfish Williams, we called him, Williams.
[SPEAKER_00]: Van Gelder, Danforth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sissler.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dave Danforth.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the Emory ball or the foreign substance or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Sissler, great hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit that Thompson ball, and he'd be, of course, first player to throw a shortstop and get him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could go down and talk about all-star clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: He doesn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: He really has seen them all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's seen them all.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Trish Speaker?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any trouble pitching to him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Trish was living with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would you pitch to him?
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched him outside.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was short right field, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I grew up in Cleveland, saw games there, that short right field wall.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, the Soles.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Trish was one of the greatest.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of the greatest going back after a fly ball you ever seen.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played shallow, but he didn't hit a ball that seemed like it just
[SPEAKER_01]: They say he used to make some unassisted double plays by catching the low-laners coming in, or else picking them off second.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Topper Rigney make an unassisted triple play while you were with him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Who?
[SPEAKER_01]: Rigney?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that I remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or Johnny Noone?
[SPEAKER_00]: Could have.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny Noone, I think Johnny came up a little later than he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was with Jersey City.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with the FBI League.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he made an unassisted triple play somewhere along there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're talking about Glenn Wright's unassisted triple play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Glenn Wright and then him and two guys from Pittsburgh, Trader and Ben Wright.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the fight, somebody hit a ground ball through there somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're that good, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, both of them could throw like bullets.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wright said he didn't know where he was going to go, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just broke up the concrete wall behind first base there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Charlie Grimm, he says, saved him a lot with his fancy catches there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a great ball player, Charlie.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you work much on your fielding?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do they make new pitchers that will work on your fielding, you know, to field bunts?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went through all that covering first base and, you know, fielding bunts.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think they do much of that today, do you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't drive much anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: All I do is drive over to the store.
[SPEAKER_01]: Work on their fundamentals.
[SPEAKER_01]: When was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: The 50th anniversary?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1976?
[SPEAKER_00]: down to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they invited us back to St. Louis for the 50th anniversary.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the doctor didn't want me to go alone, so I took my son along.
[SPEAKER_00]: I paid his way and mine too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was eight of us living.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Sir Jess Haynes was alive, but he didn't like that he was home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob O'Farrell was there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll be darned.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the first baseman on that team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wouldn't be there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Frisch wouldn't have been there.
[SPEAKER_00]: What?
[SPEAKER_00]: Frisch wouldn't have been there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Frisch wasn't with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He probably would have passed away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I mean, Frisch wasn't even with you then.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm afraid the year after that wasn't for Hornby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dowsett, Tanner Dowsett.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Ernie Orsatti with that team?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ernie Orsatti, or did he come in later?
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't on that team in 2016.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Pepper Martin was on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd passed away.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there was just eight of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's funny, I can't think of the rest of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They give it all one of those big plaques, you know, that put them back from when they first started playing ball right to the last.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a picture of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll show it to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll bring it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you, Hank.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rita.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's beautiful.
[SPEAKER_01]: You did pretty good artwork, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a couple of them, I can see.
Isn't that beautiful?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's like it appears in who's who in baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the way your record appears in who's who in baseball, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, the whole thing, even the World Series, outside of the 2060, I didn't get in any ballgames in the 2060s.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was on the roster, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Even got right to the first start, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Port 20.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 13, lost 22.
[SPEAKER_01]: 12 and 26.
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I just didn't have that kind of a club.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched good balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, your ERA was pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: 3.82.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched good balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, you've had long seasons out there in the Coast League, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: What?
[SPEAKER_01]: Long seasons.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 100 and 200 games, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you pitch against Paul Strand out there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember Paul Strand?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wasn't he with Salt Lake?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he got over 300 hits one year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Rummer was up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Earl Sheely.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember Earl Sheely?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with Salt Lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Strand had such a great year, and they paid so much money for him, the athletics, and he couldn't do a thing up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just missed out on that pitching, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Major League pitching, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Three or four years, I just... You know, Garagiola... Garagiola, he started something...
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't last very long, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: Tried to get some of these old-timers like myself... Been up the majors for... 10, 12, 15 years or better, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Get them some kind of a...
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitch, and you know what I mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was up there 17 and a half years.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I had a little bit more time, well.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were up there more than most of them by far.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 542 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you get right at that age, you know where you could, every little thing would help.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know about the modern players.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just ignored the old timers, the modern players and their pension.
[SPEAKER_01]: These guys are up for four years, and they get a pension.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the minimum, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, four years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I thought, I don't know, baseball now, not only baseball, but to me, all sports has gone a little bit overhead.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, the average person, you know, $6, $7, $8 a year, the physicians can hardly do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Basketball, same way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like sports.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like all kinds of sports.
[SPEAKER_00]: I participated in a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Golf.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do in the off-season during your career?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not much of anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hunt?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fish?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fish.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of fishing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Played golf.
[SPEAKER_01]: You kept in shape pretty well then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I did small jobs.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when spring training came, you were ready to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What were some of the toughest batters you faced?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, gosh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Trying to get out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any standouts?
[SPEAKER_00]: There were so many of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, the greatest ball player I hit that ever put on a pair of ball shoes was Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you mentioned Babe Ruth, the first thing that hit her was your man, Home Run.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there's a fella that still holds the World Series record of pitching, I think, in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: A great outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: He can throw like a bullet.
[SPEAKER_00]: A good baserunner.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one of the best personalities a man could ever meet.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he called everybody kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, if he'd beat the president, he'd say, I didn't know you, kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody was a kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've seen him many times in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had that big Packard sedan, you know, after the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a new club every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come out here, didn't have to have one broke in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd take them and throw them up in the stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when he'd get dressed, he'd go out in the parking lot with his car, and there'd be a whole band of kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd sit in the running board and sign the kids' autographs.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd let them load as many as he could, get in the Packard, take them over to the subway, or wherever they're going.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was a great guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Harry Heilman like?
[SPEAKER_00]: Good fella.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there a tension between Heilman and Cobb at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: A little.
[SPEAKER_00]: How they call them appreciators and stuff like that, you know.
What?
[SPEAKER_00]: What for?
[SPEAKER_00]: They say there's a lot of truth, but Harry had it in his contract to keep us out of argument.
[SPEAKER_00]: With time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I'm saying.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not for sure, but I think it's come from pretty good source.
[SPEAKER_00]: But a lot of remarks he'd make, you know, I see it in him in many a fight, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like what Efti was traded to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it Boston or Chicago?
[SPEAKER_00]: Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he pitched the World Series game against Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that was a good game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in Philadelphia then.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to Boston before that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he was traded.
[SPEAKER_00]: Philadelphia, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, we were playing in Detroit, and the first time the cop got up there, Nepke was pitching, down he goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's throwing bricks at him.
[SPEAKER_00]: After the game, he's the first one out of there, out of the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, he got that empty down and got a hold of his hair and he said, you still mean it?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a pretty big man to get down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was tall.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a real big scrawl feller.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a lot of fights.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shocker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a fight with Shocker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Marbury, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Marbury.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd ever get in battle with Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he'd fight, he'd cut his own mother to get on base, tie with.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got a hand in two matters.
[SPEAKER_01]: You really never pitched against him, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: You were always on his side, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had so many good hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, gosh, I'm afraid I could lose them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you, you, Jerry, and the Wainers, and sisters,
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if I should just keep my pictures the same way as Alexander, not Madison, but who were before me, Dizzy, Dizzy Dean.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw him high fastball outside and hit that long fly ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Throw many of these brushback pitches?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had that.
[SPEAKER_00]: You get orders to do that?
[SPEAKER_00]: What's the signal again?
[SPEAKER_00]: 2, 3, and then 3 and 3.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then our fastball was 2 and 1.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, different, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you go on your knees or something like that to be the second sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd go through all that in the spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a lot of times they'd get a man on second base, they'd change, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, the shortstop would be relaying it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He gets back up here with his hand, open or packed, and then the center fielder gets an idea of what's thrown too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, whether they do all that now or not, but they used to relay some fun signs of the shortstop, shortstop relay, the second baseman relays it on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you get a different break on the ball, too, if you like.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the manager called the brushback pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the manager order you to throw that pitch?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or did you just?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I remember one time he had a pitch against the athletics in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jimmy Dykes was hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tom was playing in the center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I forget who was coaching on third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, he gave me... We played Dykes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was about to throw a curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It didn't hurt.
[SPEAKER_01]: He signaled you to throw the curve?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He signaled the coach?
[SPEAKER_00]: The coach signaled Jimmy Dykes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was coaching more of the athletics.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had tipped him off.
[SPEAKER_00]: I found that out later.
[SPEAKER_00]: He tipped him off with a curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably got a flash from the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it didn't curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stepped into it and hit him right in the back of the ear.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just went over like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Blood coming out of his nose.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, that scared the heck out of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't want to hit him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted to brush him back.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he stepped into it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like a curveball, he stepped into it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he stepped into a fast one, and that was pretty fast.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that upset you for pitching after that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: The cop erased him because I hit him in the head with a duster.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was I going to do?
[SPEAKER_00]: The only fine I ever got in my life was $10 from him for not coming close enough to a hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: $10 for all the years I played ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only time I ever got.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it made it stick, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, did he come in from center field much and consult with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how you manage from way out in center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's kind of tricky.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he'd look around.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd look around.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a knockdown sign or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd reach down and get a plate of grass and put it in his mouth.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd have to turn around and look and see him do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sure enough, here's Bassler with a...
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the boy was looking last night to get a picture of the 1926 Carlo team.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was just looking for a picture of the 1926 team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jess Haines.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jess Haines doesn't live far from us.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were over visiting him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got a couple of those big team pictures up in his little den there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he's got the same one of the 1926 team.
[SPEAKER_00]: 31, then 30, 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 26 was the big one for Jess, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He pitched against the Yankees in that series.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say his damn knuckles were bleeding, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But a knuckleball pitcher, Jess was, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get to know Alexander very well?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he take such poor care of himself, as they say?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a lot of times, you know, you pick up the paper, you see that they find Alexander in the gutter or some darn place, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's subject to epileptic.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, you get one of these damn fits, and away he goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Alex would drink, too, but most of the time,
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one time in Cincinnati, we were getting ready to go to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where the car goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had his straw hats on, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were sitting in the lobby there, sitting in the hotel.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of a sudden, Pete gets up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just stares around, and down he goes.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we all run over and got a hold of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he come in one of those epileptics.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he come in and got in the
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I went up in Philadelphia, got into one of those downy goes, and a whole ball club went around, circled around him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Trader, Doc Weaver, they'd come out and, gee, they got ahold of his tongue, you know, said, let's swallow his tongue.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started on his windup, you know, wind it up like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don Hurst was the hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he didn't let that ball go, Don was dumbfounded.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went over for strikes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here Pete went down.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then they helped him with the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was done for the day.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mean he had a seizure right in the mound?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So maybe some of these times where he was said to have been drunk, he was just having an attack.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did drink, but maybe not as much.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the rest of us, we would go to a little bit overboard once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought it was Prohibition where you couldn't get any booze.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where'd you go to get it during Prohibition?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you could get it almost anyplace, speakeasies, you know, in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could write a book.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'd do it all over again, but I'd make a few different pitches, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had you pitched Eddie Roush at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess he was a left-hand hitter, a pretty good one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the chap who didn't like spring training.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever hold out any yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the years of St. Louis, Jimmy Wilson would catch them most of the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're great catchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quite a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he your favorite?
[SPEAKER_00]: One of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You have favorite catchers, I mean.
[SPEAKER_01]: Are there those you can work better with than others?
[SPEAKER_00]: I work good with Jimmy, Jimmy Wilson.
[SPEAKER_01]: You learn to understand each other, what's the best pitches?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever shake him off much?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd shake off him, but I'd come right back the same way.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might give me a curveball, and I'd raise your nose like that, and come right back with a curve.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty tricky.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if you're hitting up there, just for a second, you might wonder, what the hell is he going to throw me?
[SPEAKER_01]: How was your spitball?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I can throw at every ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I could, I say, because it was outlawed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, when we left Portland in 1921, Walter McQueen, he registered all of us, spitballs, spitballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we were eligible then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even though you'd been in the minors?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know about the major leagues, but we were eligible in the Coast League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they had spitballers up there, Shocker, and Iron Spitzel, and who was the great one over?
[SPEAKER_00]: Burleigh Grimes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kovaleski.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kovaleski and who was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Quinn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were quite a few of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had quite a few of them that could throw that good little rough spot on the ball, you know, and do tricks with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You said you could throw the Emory ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would you get it scuffed?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a lot of times it would hit the ground or something, you know, and put a scuff on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of times now, if it hits the ground, how far do I want to see the ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they go through a lot of them now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I guess the original Emory ball had a... Well, it used to have a spot on the belt, a little piece of Emory paper, and they could just... Well, that's before my time, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know it?
[SPEAKER_00]: That red paper, it wasn't a great...
[SPEAKER_00]: Clarence Mitchell, he could left-hand a spitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd really slobber off.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd hit him down a pepper martin, you know, hit the ground ball down a pepper, get ahold of that ball, and probably get ahold of that spit, and the way, the damn thing would go way up into the bleachers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought the infielders got good dirt in their hands before that ball was thrown, so they could... Oh, I used to spit in my hat and rub it like that, but I... That wasn't frowned upon?
[SPEAKER_00]: Towards the last, I'd throw a few screwballs, too, you know, to get her with my fastball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the reverse curve?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, reverse, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that kind of hard on your elbow or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not a natural.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, there's a certain way you can hold that ball and make it dip, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you hold it cross-seam, that's the way it is.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I'd hold it wide cross-seam and go like that in the bowl and catch these four seams going around.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of spin on it, see, and it'd take off a little.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if you throw it this way with just a little dip and hold on to the end of the seam, it's following two seams.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't get that resistance, so you dip.
[SPEAKER_00]: You get a dip on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to throw a lot of that to Mel Ott with the Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a tough one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the big first baseman, what the heck was his name again?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Giants?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Terry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Terry, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That Jackson, the Terry Minstrelman.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had quite a ball club, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they won a couple of pennants for that team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play some night baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, how'd you like pitching under the lights?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess the lights were very bright at first, were they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Our club was in the first night game.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou Chiazzi got the first hit, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember, but I know I always hit a lot of funnels.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to hit one up by the lights, but I couldn't do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Must have been quite an experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then it started a little bit, you know, and then they come up with that yellow baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to have two or three of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Freddie Fitzsimmons has one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whatever happened to them, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were yellow.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were supposed to be seen better at night.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd forgotten about that, but he's got one on his mantelpiece.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you get a lot of the umpires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm a nice fleeing umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: And who was it coming down?
[SPEAKER_00]: Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where Jimmy Wilson was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now he's in Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: He left the Cardinals and went over to Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can see that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And anyway, they come into town.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget who was coaching first, third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, the first ball pitch in the ball game was a foul tip and hit Quigley right on the Adam's apple, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Only at that time they had two umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Moran and Quigley were the two umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't, boy, they had to take him to the hospital.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't, boy, you know, get a foul tip right by him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, Charlie came over to the dugout then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, I don't know, he was one of the boys to umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, Bob said, sure, ask Larry Benton first.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, how about Sill down the end of the bench?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob said, OK. Charlie Moran said, you go to first base umpire the first five innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I forget the coach was Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Brooklyn, who it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one of his players upfired third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I said, well, the four innings is still coming over, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: So five innings of the first five innings, I had two or three plays just like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we went up against Cincinnati on home ground.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when the five innings was over, I started walking around.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Charlie Ryan says, where are you going?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, five innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I go back to first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, those close plays, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, two weeks later here I got a check for 25 bucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: National League for umpires.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I was a National League umpire for one game.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just picked you at random, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a pretty good choice.
[SPEAKER_01]: They must have respected your... Well, when I was with Seattle at the end, I was coaching, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spring training, I'd do most of the umpire for the interleague, inter-squad games, to see what the pitchers they got, too, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Skiff was our manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Freddie Hutchinson out there yet?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Freddie was just before, after Freddie.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's quite a pitcher out here, Freddie.
Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Ad Liska?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a Portlander.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lives out here, doesn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a sign armer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Got his second stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't go to major leagues much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think he's up there just to get some heavy butter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got his record here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just five years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he up there that long, was he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it Washington, was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and he only won 17 and lost 18.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he had quite a Coast League record, though, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, my record's just a little over 500.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got an awful lot of relief for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I noticed that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was somewhere around 101 and 104 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: 112 and 117.
[SPEAKER_00]: 112, 117?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I thought it was pretty close.
[SPEAKER_01]: 2,165 innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quite a few.
[SPEAKER_00]: for so much relief work, too, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's at a time when relief pitching just wasn't done very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have any real specialists.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: You may have been one of the first ones to really.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim Lindsay and I were with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: First part of the ball game, we'd get behind.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jim would take over, see if they'd start hitting the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: That last part of the ball game, we'd get close.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or one runner behind or one run ahead.
[SPEAKER_01]: take the pitcher off for a hitter, then I'd have to go in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whose idea was this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Self-management.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gabby Street was one of the starters.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's really a new thing in baseball, bringing in your pitchers that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the old days, I thought they gave the ball to the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went out there and stayed out there no matter what happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: The whole game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Roger Peckinpah once said that Fred Marbury
[SPEAKER_01]: But Washington was the first real good relief pitcher that made him think that this was the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, wasn't he with Farnbury?
[SPEAKER_00]: Wasn't he with Brooklyn?
[SPEAKER_00]: Wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was with Washington in the mid-'20s, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was quite a relief pitcher, I thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I thought he was with Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: He may have been later, but I think he tackled Pollock good in Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Roger?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Roger's a little bit ahead of me, too, a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd like to add Roger Pollocker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an old courtman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I was talking to Louie Guisto down here in Napa and he said Holliker was, went up with him I guess, was on the Portland team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Guisto said that Holliker and Bigby were three of them that came up about the same time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever bat against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he hit me right in the left arm once.
[SPEAKER_00]: With a curveball, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm glad it wasn't the fast one.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't think he hit anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know what I mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, our pitchers are hit sometimes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I sat a little bit too close to that plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: The curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Walter, he's hit good stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's no question about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get hit off him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get a hit off him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that I can remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: I probably did, but I don't just remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have a favorite park to pitch in?
[SPEAKER_00]: Cincinnati is one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can pitch bid ball in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a Chicago Cubs park, too, and Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can pitch bid ball in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to start a lot of cloud field games in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, after the year, their ball club wasn't too hot either.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who managed them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Dresden, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Dresden.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you get along with Dresden?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Schoenberg says he couldn't, didn't get along with Dresden.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's one of those guys, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's on me one day, too, and I challenge him to go home with the pictures of mine and go to the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't laugh to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he was laughing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, we all get our jumps and downs one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a real job, being a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: handling the people, all these different kinds of personalities to deal with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Get the best out of each one.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not easy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like Gabby.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like Gabby Street.
[SPEAKER_00]: O'Farrill was a good fellow to play for.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jimmy Wilson, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jimmy and I were like that anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Hornsby?
[SPEAKER_00]: Roger, really talented.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cobbish.
[SPEAKER_00]: A little temperamental, but good ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't go back after a fly ball and pop up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd have a heck of a time.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what Glenn Wright was saying.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was good on double plays.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a better hitter, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was all business, I guess, with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: All business and horses.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any big thrills that stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think the first time I ever pitched to the Babe was one of the biggest thrills I ever got.
[SPEAKER_00]: Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then my first game in the Major League, of course, with Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then that no-hit game I pitched to the Buffaloes when I was with Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can still see that last out, the big pop-up to third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there's so many different things.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you walk many, or hit any, that game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I always had good control.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't a perfect game, though, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No hit at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: That must have been a big thrill.
[SPEAKER_00]: I probably walked so many, but I know there was a line driver, so I was in the second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a double play on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can remember that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't always remember that high pop-up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the?
[SPEAKER_01]: lowest hit game you pitched in the majors you ever had?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, gosh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a couple of one-hit games, a couple of two-hit games.
[SPEAKER_00]: But like I say, I never started too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've done an awful lot of remit for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up with a base that's full.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one day in St. Louis, playing against Boston, that's when Hornsby was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Les Bell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby and Les Bell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chardelle was pitching for us, and they had that tuberculosis day in St. Louis at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we were ahead one run going into the ninth inning, and Chardelle pitching, and Boston got the bases full, and Hornsby was the hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So who goes in but me?
[SPEAKER_00]: Put me in the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I strike Hornsby out, and made one out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I struck Bell out and made two out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I forget the next hitter, but anyway, it was a big pop-up to the third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got Hornsby, Bell, and that pop-up.
[SPEAKER_00]: We win the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: That, to me, was one of the greatest jobs I ever made.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's real pressure pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to pitch right in there to Roger, and I pitched right in there to Les Bell.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was like high fast balls, that crowd of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hartman, and Demery, and you know those fellas that when Demery first came up, he was a high ball, he was supposed to be a high ball hitter, but I'd pitch high at home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd pitch my own strength, but there's not much to say over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the ball, you've got to hit it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't say that as long as you make a hit, you've got a chance.
[SPEAKER_00]: You walk up, you don't have a chance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, there's times that base opens, and you will walk it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about your move to first base?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any problems with that at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that catches pretty good arms, too, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I'd throw over to first base,
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I said, as a fastball pitcher, they don't get little breaks a lot of times on the fastball pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Especially the high ballers right there with, you know, Phil Goodow would have been.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you really met and played with some great people, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any, uh,
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you recall any very funny incidents happening on a ball field?
[SPEAKER_00]: Do what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you recall any funny, humorous things happening in a game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think the funniest...
[SPEAKER_00]: I probably should have said, I'd say this, was with Flint Rembrandt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Flint Rembrandt was, you know, he used to drink quite a bit, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he came out one time in Cincinnati to start the ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got in that pitcher's mouth and he couldn't get set.
[SPEAKER_00]: He threw the first one and it went over the catcher's head and got darned net, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He threw another one just about as bad, and then he walks off the mound.
[SPEAKER_00]: He goes over to the groundkeeper's place over there and he gets a shovel.
[SPEAKER_00]: He comes out with the rubber, you know, and starts digging a hole in that shovel where he can get his foot.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that didn't help anything, so they finally knew what the hell was the matter with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thank God about it, but to me that was the funniest way to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why'd he come out with that shovel?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, if he got his feet lower down, the ball wouldn't go so high up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he'd get his toe over that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any pictures, extra pictures of yourself you might be able to autograph for me?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's something I don't have.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish I could get some.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't have any?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know who to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish I did have them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I really don't have a picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: You sent them all?
[SPEAKER_00]: I get letters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I get two or three or four letters every week.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish I knew where I could get some of those pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd like to send them to the kids, but I really don't have one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm sure as heck give it to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You did have them, but they've all gone, is that it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to have so many of them as chewing gum and stuff like that, you know, to sign up for.
[SPEAKER_01]: I may have one of you on a chewing gum.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you probably have.
[SPEAKER_00]: So often you get a regular postcard size, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would be either Phillies or mostly Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then a lot of them were the Cardinals, and not too many were Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's been a very interesting interview.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, thank you very much for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish there was a lot more, but like I say, a fellow could keep asking questions and probably always write a book if he had time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Looks like 26 years here from your first year with Portland down to Vancouver.
[SPEAKER_01]: 27 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last year, when I went up to Vancouver to manage.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in, what year was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: 46.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I quit in June.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went scouting with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long did you scout with the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_00]: About three years, a little better, with Joe Devine.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was up in the Northwest here.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I'd be working at Reynolds Aluminum Plant, too, at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I had a very, very farm out here.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'd catch the colleges and the high schools, you know, around town here and send in reports.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anybody you recommend ever make it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, a couple of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Morrison was one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, oh, I had a couple of good-looking kids, but then everybody was after them, and they turned out to be just couldn't make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the most, bonus every year was $4,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, it was a high bonus, $4,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't get nothing when I went up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got $400 a month for the tight job.
[SPEAKER_00]: With Detroit?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about later on?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get much more?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, about $5,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: And about Thompson?
[SPEAKER_00]: Thompson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ruth, he was the highest price paid.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was supposed to be $80,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the middle of the Depression, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: What would he get now?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's unbelievable how high he could hit them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've seen him hit many a ball up in the infield of Whitbow a little bit, and it just staggered, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He put the second plate standing up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was quite a player.
[SPEAKER_01]: The very first game I ever saw, he had a home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, where was this at?
[SPEAKER_01]: Cleveland in 1929.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that right field wasn't too awful far away, either.
[SPEAKER_00]: Centerfield was the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one time Spoke, we all called him Spoke, the speaker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I'd pitch him outside and he'd hit it right down that left field line just before it got down to, used to be a, left the stand, used to switch around a little bit, but damn boy, it went right in between the gate like this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, it was a two-base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what that was.
[SPEAKER_01]: People like Averill were my heroes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, he was a little later with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had Luke and Joey Sowell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Luke Sowell was catching, and oh, gosh, I forget those.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had Eddie Morgan.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I say, some clubs I can remember, like Detroit, some I can remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every player.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Philadelphia, most of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Cincinnati, because I was only in Cincinnati a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Jimmy Wilson, like I said, when Jimmy Wilson come through with the Phillies, he said, I'm going to take you back to Philadelphia with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, oh, get out of here.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a bad box, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sure enough, the service was over.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got called from Cincinnati, you're traded to Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was when Shulman Riggins' client hand says, Ruble, come over to
[SPEAKER_00]: Cincinnati from Philadelphia and it wasn't it wasn't